<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tutorials on Thavanathan</title>
    <link>http://example.org/tutorials/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tutorials on Thavanathan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2020 16:14:00 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://example.org/tutorials/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Variables and Simple data structures</title>
      <link>http://example.org/tutorials/python-beginner/variables/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2020 16:14:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/tutorials/python-beginner/variables/</guid>
      <description>Introduction As in any other language, Python has variables as we some simple common data types like int, float, string&amp;hellip; In this section we will see how variables are working in Python and how to use these simple data types.
Variables As we said already, in Python, everything is an object. For example strings, numbers, True, False&amp;hellip; etc. Like all objects in real world have names, we name Python objects too.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with interpreter</title>
      <link>http://example.org/tutorials/python-beginner/2019-11-20-getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2019 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/tutorials/python-beginner/2019-11-20-getting-started/</guid>
      <description>3.1 Python Interactive Interpreter In the previous section, we saw how to install Python in various operating system. Now let&amp;rsquo;s learn how to use Python Interactive Interpreter and how to run a python program.
If you are using Windows open command prompt and type python. If you are using Mac, open Terminal and type python. open Console and type python in Linux.
This command opens Python interactive interpreter like the one shown below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing Python</title>
      <link>http://example.org/tutorials/python-beginner/2019-11-17-installing-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2019 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/tutorials/python-beginner/2019-11-17-installing-python/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In this post we will learn about installing Python on Windows, Mac and Linux.
Windows Download python from https://www.python.org/downloads/. You will see multiple versions of Python listed over there. 3.7.1 is the latest stable version at the time of writing this post. Select 3.7.1 link as shown in the below figure.
After selecting a particular version of Python you will see all the platform specific setup files over there like the one below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python Introduction</title>
      <link>http://example.org/tutorials/python-beginner/2019-11-14-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2019 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/tutorials/python-beginner/2019-11-14-introduction/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Python is a general purpose programming language. First version of Python was released around the year 1991. Python syntax is inspired by C syntax, but it is much easier than that. If you are coming from other languages like C or Java, first thing you will notice that Python doesn&amp;rsquo;t use curly braces or semi colons. Even though Semi-colons are allowed, nobody really uses it.
Python is majorly used in following areas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Django Introduction</title>
      <link>http://example.org/categories/title/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2019 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/categories/title/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Python&amp;rsquo;s CGI library is good enough for writing websites from ground up. But we need to put a lot of effort into it to build a usable and secure website. When building a web application we often come across some common tasks like authenticating users, connecting to a database, sending emails to users, a reliable admin interface to manage and add content to our site, etc. If we solve all of these problems ourselves, it is time-consuming.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CGI Programming with Python</title>
      <link>http://example.org/categories/title/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2018 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/categories/title/</guid>
      <description>If you have read the previous post, we stopped after introducing web servers. In this post, we write very simple web application using cgi programming.
CGI stands for Common Gateway Interface. Let&amp;rsquo;s say we received a web request, and we want to process that request with Python. CGI is basically a script that is run by the web server whenever a request is received. The script can be a Python script or a Shell script or Ruby script.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web Servers and clients</title>
      <link>http://example.org/categories/title/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/categories/title/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Web programming or web development is a term that broadly means developing websites. Developing websites mainly consists of two parts.
 Front end development. Back end development.  Front end includes html, javascript and css. We can also say it is the creativity part. If you are more interested in creating beautiful websites, this is the path you should take. Backend involves in server side development including application business logic, database design and development, server deployment and maintenance and etc.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>